So in the world of AI assisted
development and AIcentric development,
obviously the the level of speed up that
we see from code creation is intense.
And one of the areas that really then
start becoming a pinch, becoming a
bottleneck is how do we actually review
that code? How do we actually validate
that the code is is that is being
generated at speed is of the right
quality. Um so
we have Snehar Tuli here who is the
principal product manager at Microsoft.
Uh and Snehar is going to be talking
about how AI assisted code reviews on
PRs can work at scale and this is based
on Snehar's experience at Microsoft and
how some of their learnings uh across
this roll out uh occurred. So um please
give a very warm welcome to Sneha.
[music]
>> Hello everyone. It is a privilege to be
here amongst all of you who are not only
helping shape how we code but also the
future of how we will work and live in
years ahead. I will be talking about AI
assisted code reviews on pull request.
how we scaled it from a proof of concept
to full-fledged rollout in the in one of
the world's largest engineering
organization.
I would like to ground ourselves into
some magnitude. We are talking here a
company with more than 100k engineers,
product managers and designers, more
than 800k PRs created and reviewed on a
monthly basis and 150k repositories. You
can only imagine the extent we are
talking here. the vast code base, the
diversity in each team's conventions,
best practices, frameworks, and even
security requirements.
Making sure quality and security at this
scale is a massive undertaking.
In most of the large organizations,
there's immense pressure to boost
developer productivity and that we want
to empower our developers so that they
can ship high quality code at a very
rapid pace. That does not only mean
coding fast but also means reviewing at
a fast pace such that it safeguards
quality and security. But what is the
reality?
How many times your PRs are just stuck
over and you're waiting if not days at
least hours for someone to give first
pass on the review. As a reviewer, is it
really exciting to deep dive into
someone else's code and spend time in
reviewing each and every line?
There are inconsistent review practices
as you switch teams. And also often
times because of tight constraints
some obvious or nonobvious critical
issues can slip into production.
We [snorts] had a hypothesis why don't
we use AI for routine checks and
reviewers only focus on on 10 to 20% of
the checks that really deserve their
expertise. We put this hypothesis to
test and what happened. Today we review
more than 90% of the pull requests in
the company impacting more than 95% of
the developers. Based on different
experiments we have seen 10 to 20%
improvement in PR completion time
and also our usefulness rating is
between 50 to 60%. The scale at which we
are talking about it's hundreds and
thousands of suggestions that get
accepted and even thousands of hours
that get saved.
I'll just quickly gl mention what we
developed and then I will talk about the
learnings and lessons along the way and
I hope you will be able to take some
practical learnings that you can
incorporate in your AI journey. What did
we build? First of all, anytime a pull
request gets created, we left a summary
on that pull request which would
describe at very high level what this
pull request is about and key changes in
this pull request. This was important
for reviewers to glance through what the
what are they getting into before even
they review the PR.
Then AI would automatically immediately
again as a PR gets created review the
content of the PR and if there are any
suggestions it would post comments
aligned with the change lines so that
reviewers can fix them. It would also
give a suggestion of exactly how this
can be resolved. And lastly, there is an
interactive Q&A where reviewers or
developers can ask questions like is
this method fine or is there any other
better alternative?
And again, it's a collaborative space.
Everything is on the PR thread. The way
human reviewers and developers interact
with each other.
When we started, we started really small
with caution. This was in 2023
when AI had just started. We did not
know what to expect. We did not know
what the impact is going to be. So we
started with some repositories. The very
first thing we did was we developed a
feedback collection mechanism even
before rolling it out. Not only thumbs
up, thumbs down, verbatim feedback and
we came up with creative ways to
understand suggestion acceptance rate.
For verbatim feedback, we sent all of it
to LLM to take a pass at what's working
and what needs improvement.
Then prompt engineering the very basic
capability that everyone has to work on
even before they are starting a project.
We worked on iteratively.
We wanted a prompt that is not very
complex for LLM to understand like like
get confused or it's not too short for
it to start assuming things. But what
worked the most is prompt version
control. We started versioning our
prompts and then tracked the usefulness.
Why did we do that? We realized with
minor changes with prom it can have
significant impact on the usefulness.
For example, initially our comments were
pretty verbose. The suggestions we had
to literally scroll through the comment
to get to what the AI is suggesting.
Well, that's an exaggeration, but you
get the point. We updated the prompt to
say please be clear and precise while
explaining.
And with that, we saw the usefulness
improved by 5%. Whereas on the other
scenario, we updated the prompt to say
anytime you see high severity issue,
flag it as critical. We thought
developers will like it, but our
usefulness rating rating went down. Why?
Now AI was just commenting on high
severity issues and not the holistic
picture and that was a miss at our end.
We reverted back. Hence having a prompt
version control system that monitors
prompt version the prompt changes with
the usefulness is very important.
By now we were getting positive signals
and we knew we could roll it out a bit
broadly. So we enabled it to 5% of the
company's PRs.
The feedback we were getting initially
we were posting just one blob of comment
with all the suggestions in it. Why? We
did not want to spam the reviewers or
developers with too many comments.
But then what happened? Our developers
did not want that. They wanted a
humanlike experience. The way they would
if they are commenting on someone's PR,
they would pick a line or a div and
comment on that. They won't leave a blob
of comment. And that's exactly what they
wanted.
We did AB testing and we see we saw a
difference of 20% in usefulness rating.
It was significant. We adapted. Hence we
integrated into the existing workflow
and experience. That's what developers
want. They don't want a new experience
crafted all together.
The quality of suggestion is important
but so is integration. Ease of
integrating that experience. In our
case, developers did not want to say
that comment, go back to IDE, make
changes and come back. They wanted it to
be easy and quick to apply that
suggestion. We came up with this apply
change feature. We integrated this and
developers could write their create a
new iteration on the PR.
This one is my favorite. Whenever we
were getting feedback, developers were
saying AI is asking me to make this
change which is incorrect.
I want to highlight the word asking.
Never did they say it's suggesting. We
went back to the comments and we
realized that AI is sometimes being too
assertive. It is using words like this
will fail because of XX reason. So we
changed our prompt for AI to be
encouraging and supportive. Our
suggestion started showing up as this
could be problematic. It would be better
to do this. And again our suggestion
acceptance increased with this because
developers were now seeing it as a buddy
versus a faultfinder.
We had to earn trust. Initially we were
kind of spamming the developers with lot
many comments. So we created a small
language model
based on the past reviews. So anytime a
PR was created the diffs were passed
through this SLM which was hosted by us.
Not only did it save cost but only
important risky diffs were not were now
getting sent to LLM. This reduced the
noise significantly. We started earning
trust and then we knew like we could
lower the thresholds once we have earned
the trust and go to an optimal threshold
of what riskiness or what level of
issues each team wants.
By now we had a system which we knew has
earned the trust of the developers and
was working well integrated into the PR
loop. But we had different set of
challenges. The other half of the puzzle
was still remaining. What will happen if
we scale it across the company with so
many different code bases.
There's so much variation by each team.
For one team, using a method would be
difficult. They don't want it because of
performance issues. For another team,
they might have some steps of security
they want to be followed. So we gave
teams the option they could specify
repository specific instructions or even
create custom prompts for their
repository which AI would take into
account while reviewing. With this we
could increase our scope our user base
because now if teams want a different
experience they had the option to do
that.
Missing context. This is a common one.
The context of each codebase is
different. If we just send the pull
request details and a method is used or
referenced which AI has no idea what is
the definition behind this method then
the reviews will be irrelevant.
So we work through semantic search graph
rack and we are I will be candid
continuously even now working on it.
It's not a resolved scenario on what's
the right optimal
u context that LLM needs for the best
review.
Multi-agent orchestration if you have
not heard it enough throughout all the
sessions I'll repeat it so we had a
review agent we also came up with a
critic agent why because there were
misses LLM was making instead of having
all those instructions and processes in
the review agent we came up with a
critic agent review agent would first
come up with a suggestion this critic
agent would look for things like are the
suggestions really associated with
changed lines of code because sometimes
it can provide recommend commendations
on changes the developer has not made as
a part of that pull request and
developers do not want that. So review
critic agent combination really worked
for us. Also we saw differences based on
language types C++ even files. So we
came up with language specific agents so
that we could give best practices or
true information that mattered for AI to
review.
And lastly, AB testing framework very
important.
It's not just a product development
good to have anymore. It's a core
capability. Anytime a new model comes
in, you might want to just jump into
update that new model into your product.
But is that model LLM model really
making a difference significant
difference for you to go and try it out
or change the entire user experience to
that model? That needs to be validated
before you even roll that out. Maybe
it's a marginal difference. Maybe it's
same.
By now again we not only had a product
which has scale which was scalable
across the company. It had on trust was
a decent quality
with any product. Security is very
important. You need to have guardrails
for safety and compliance.
From the very beginning, we made sure we
had processes in place to detect and
ignore any malicious instru instructions
so that there is no prompt injection.
Any unsafe or sensitive output such as
credentials do not show up.
We had systems in place to apply
emergency break anytime there was any
anomaly like we could roll back
immediately. We could turn it off and
just go back to human reviews if need
be. Human
in the loop very crucial AI can suggest
but if that suggestion is worth
accepting that decision is on a human
and with this
just like any human review they would
leave a comment and it's on the
developer if they want to accept it
dismiss it or debate over it similarly
with our AI comment they could do the
same and transparency any AI suggestion
should be pointed out as coming from AI
and the human who reviews it should be
held accountable and they have to use
their judgment before accepting it. This
is a core I would say principle we have
been following.
Hence
following user feedback giving teams the
option to customize their experience
transparency and integrating into the
existing workflow. All of this worked
really well for us. What's ahead? Not
just for us but for the industry
overall.
Exciting direction.
Planner. There will be multiple agents.
One planner which will diagnose and
devise the next steps. It will take it
to next level. If an API is getting
updated, it needs to have proper
authorization and authentication in
place. If there is a complex business
logic, it needs to have right unit
tests, integration tests. If a
dependency is updated, there should be
downstream compatibility. Hence, review
should be taking a big deeper uh
experience into account.
More context does not always mean better
decisions. AI can get confused. So AIS
will become LL our agents will become
smart enough to decide what is the right
context for a particular scenario. In
some case it might want to look into
previous commits and in some cases it
might want to pull in some
documentation.
For both of this good planning and
better context we need to give AI the
right tools in a secure manner. If it
has to pull the previous historical PRs
it should have the tool for that. If it
has to pull unit test file, it should
have a tool for that
memory retention. It will go to next
level where it will start learning. If a
team repeatedly dismisses a particular
type of suggestion, it should be added
into its best practice or its knowledge
base that this kind of suggestion I
should not be giving to this team.
There's something off. If there is a
production defect, it should feed back
into the review process so that that
does not happen again.
And lastly, transparency. It needs to
explain the reasoning so that developers
really find it trustworthy to accept the
suggestion.
For example, if it is asking to add a
validation and it references past PR in
which the validation was added to avoid
any injection attacks that earns the
trust of developer and they are more
prone to accept the suggestion.
Soon AI will start scheduling coffee
breaks for us. one you might be needing
right now.
In closing,
AI is here to help augment our
experiences.
We really need to give the right context
to AI to get better output. Human in the
loop is crucial. AI can suggest this is
a better method to be used, but is it
truly better is the decision we have to
make. It can schedule a coffee break for
me. But today, am I in the mood of
drinking espresso or coffee latte? That
decision is on me. It is a revolutionary
time. We have to accept. We have to
adapt. Thank you.
[applause]
>> Okay.
>> Awesome. Any questions at all?
>> One sec. I'm just going to I'll come
back to you.
>> Hello.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh the question that I had was does this
already exist in um latest releases of
co-pilot?
>> Sorry.
>> Does this already exist this agent?
>> It is our learnings internally whatever
we learned it has also helped influence
GitHub copilot code review.
>> Mhm.
>> So yes, GitHub has a code review service
which is slightly different like this is
internal because it has more context of
our code bases etc. But it does exist in
GitHub copilot code review experience.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I don't have this deeply thought
out, but you have 5% of your I guess the
phrasing company PRs is what I was
asking about. Do you have some kind of
is there some kind of like control point
that you have that reviews everything?
Does this is this all internally facing
code bases? Maybe
>> that is right. It is all internal
spacing code bases and anytime a pull
request gets created that's the control
point.
>> Got it. Thank you.
>> Uh I have three questions. The first
question will be um how would you um
measure the PR code review quality? So
based on my experience, if you're using
different LMS
um to review the same piece of code, it
might give you different uh review
results. And um yeah, this will be the
first question. And the second question
is that um
do uh how do you uh do the code reviews
for monor repo versus the um um
different uh across the company
different repos because um when you're
working on a single repo it's missing
the context of the overall picture
especially working on some uh
microservices distributed services they
have some dependencies. So how would you
solve that? Yeah,
>> I'll start off with the second one. This
was a very good question. So for mono
repos, we came up with an approach where
at each branch level they could specify
best practices and they generally
generally monor repos each teams do have
best practices that they follow
internally. So for each branch we gave
the capability not just repository level
even within repository level each branch
or each folder they could specify what
instructions what are the best practices
for them and especially two two of our
monor repos have been extensively using
that capability. Now coming for forward
to the usefulness we have different
indicators we have been tracking
usefulness like the votes given by
developers is something we continuously
track and that has been an impactful
metric for us we have devised our own
creative ways to come up with like what
percent is getting accepted and we saw
if we change the model like for example
when there was 03 mini and 03 versus
GPT4 so we tested based on different
languages different models and track
these different metrics that we we are
following and whichever was working best
that's where we got signals from that
okay this is the model that is working
best at this point in time in future
though it is definitely getting better
so the inconsistency you are saying
hopefully we will not see in future
models
>> we have a question online um the
question is uh
oh a thought sorry uh is that based on
that previous talk from Neil. Uh perhaps
there is an idea to combine code review
agent with with a fitness function. Um
imagine the agent detecting dependency
on an on an incorrect API and suggesting
a better one from the enterprise
catalog. Um any final questions from the
room?
No. Then I'm going to sell. Any final
questions? Feel like an auctioneer.
Wonderful. Thank you very much. Give it
up for Sneha.
>> Thank you
>> so much.
[music]
>> [music]